<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Satyakam.net</title><link href="http://www.satyaakam.net/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.satyaakam.net/feeds/community-contribute-contributions-foss-personal-social-xo.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.satyaakam.net/</id><updated>2012-03-28T09:16:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>Lets Teach our children to fail...</title><link href="http://www.satyaakam.net/lets-teach-our-children-to-fail.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-03-28T09:16:00+05:30</updated><author><name>satya</name></author><id>tag:www.satyaakam.net,2012-03-28:lets-teach-our-children-to-fail.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am surprised by the way the society is moving especially the education
system and our young tender years in school.Why do one has to be
rewarded only for passing or not to fail ? Why is passing so important
for ones well being because with that he does not learn much while one
fails he learns a lot. Why are kids who experiment and hence commit
mistakes &amp;nbsp;abhored as wrong when what they are doing is at least trying .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same pattern emerges when we grow up into young adults where being
sucessful becomes so obessesive that people go to any length to be so
called &amp;nbsp;succesful , what i am saying is it's not bad to be desiring for
sucess but the way it's played out is not ok . We as a society has laid
a wrong precident in the young minds trying to so impinging our values
and belief systems on them and how to fail is bad and sucess is the only
way to Learn .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every Kid in this world has a moral right to fail because that's the
only way we Humans learn if you stop that i think it's an impediment to
ones learning process and ultimately shows about the society and times
we are living in , where in the name of competition Students are under
tremendous pressure and loose the whole point of Learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So learning to fail and learning from failing should be our motto...
think&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Education"></category><category term="Hack"></category><category term="OLPC"></category><category term="Startups"></category></entry></feed>